Louise Elliott

Phone: 07749319196 | Email: louise.elliott.work@gmail.com | Bournemouth, UK

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/louise-elliott-work

GitHub: https://github.com/louise-elliott-work
Portfolio: https://louise-elliott-work.netlify.app

Summary

Driven and always keen to learn and adapt. Effective at problem-solving, identifying areas for improvements and supporting colleagues with up-skilling and implementing change. Known as a conscientious professional with a keen eye for detail and a passion for making a difference. Experience working in a variety of socially responsible roles. Qualified foster carer providing alternative care at weekends and during school holidays. Skillset of ever-expanding web development tools and technologies alongside varied child development expertise supported by primarily self-sourced training and development.

Technical Skills

React, Tailwind, JavaScript, JQuery, API, Node.js, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML

Projects

Culinary Compass | https://github.com/Chae-Lee/Culinary_Compass | https://culinary-compasses.netlify.app/

- Summary: Provides users with data for Michelin restaurants across the globe.
 Allows users to search by country or award, by those nearby, or to be given a random suggestion.
- Role: Developed collaboratively as part of a four-person team
- Tools: React, Tailwind, JavaScript, API

React Portfolio | https://github.com/louise-elliott-work/react-portfolio | https://louise-elliott-work.netlify.app

- Summary: Utilises React routings for smooth navigation. Displays projects in a modified carousel rendering data stored in a json file for efficiency and futureproofing. Employs useState and emailJS for contact form functionality.
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, CSS

PupVenture | https://ibalan92.github.io/dog-friendly-locations | https://github.com/ibalan92/dog-friendly-locations

- Summary: Provides users with a list of dog-friendly destinations. Allows users to input date and location to be shown nearby destinations and weather forecast data. Has additional option to save locations as favourites.
- Role: Developed collaboratively as part of a four-person team.
- Tools: APIs, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Education

Sep23 - Jan24

Front End Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: edX

An intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, ReactJS, ES6 and Node.js. Emphasis on teamwork and collaboration throughout. Grade: 97%.

Sep16 - Jul17

Post Graduate Certificate in Education - Languages: University of Brighton A practical course about how people develop, consolidate and deepen their knowledge and understanding of language in different contexts. Grade: QTS & 60 Masters credits.

Sep07 - Jul11

Bachelor of Science International Management and Spanish: University of Bath A four-year degree focused on the international business environment and the global economy. Third year spent working in Chile in audit and SAP. Grade: First Class.

Experience

Teacher of Languages

2017-2024

Kingdown School St Bartholomew's School Bohunt School

Warminster, UK Newbury, UK

Wokingham, UK

Taught French, Spanish, English and Literacy to pupils aged 11-18.

Key accomplishments:

- Delivered tailored support to pupils with 100% A level results above target.
- Communicated effectively with parents/carers, colleagues and other professionals.
- Identified and completed key training and disseminated key findings to colleagues.

Internal Auditor 2015-2016

International HIV/AIDS Alliance

Brighton, UK

Carried out audits of partner organisations and head office procedures. Key accomplishments:

- Carried out audits in Cambodia, Ecuador, Peru, Kenya, Ukraine and Namibia.
- Identified priority risk areas and recommended action points.
- Wrote clear and comprehensive reports summarising findings for key stakeholders.

Conservation Partnerships Administrator

2013-2015

Programme Finance Officer, Americas & Caribbean

2012-2013

Fauna & Flora International

Cambridge, UK

Provided financial, administrative and governance support to the organisation's five thematic teams and to the Americas & Caribbean team.

Key accomplishments:

- Streamlined communication, resource use and strategy plans across the 5 teams.
- Met 100% of internal and external financial deadlines.
- Compiled expenditure reports for \$0.5m annual project budget.